<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>About-Me on david.kun</title>
    <link>https://davidkun.github.io/tags/about-me/</link>
    <description>Recent content in About-Me on david.kun</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://davidkun.github.io/tags/about-me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>influences</title>
      <link>https://davidkun.github.io/posts/influences/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidkun.github.io/posts/influences/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We all stand on the shoulders of others. Our ability to communicate and persist our ideas and discoveries has undoubtedly had a substantial impact on our technological and social evolution.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I keep track of the books, blogs, and videos that left a mark on me and impacted my growth and development.&#xA;I do this partly to keep records (e.g., so I can go back and refresh my memory), partly to have a curated list for new developers who are interested in career growth, and partly for the potential of identifying patterns (meta-learning).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>https://davidkun.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidkun.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I started out as an aerospace engineer (designed and tested autopilot, autoland, and flight guidance control laws) and eventually grew into the software developer role. At &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mitre.org&#34;&gt;MITRE&lt;/a&gt;, I worked on aviation research software (e.g., aircraft trajectory simulation engine, near-real time airport risk detection application, and a big data platform for aviation research).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, I develop software apps in support of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ceva-ip.com/product/ceva-realspace/&#34;&gt;Spatial Audio&lt;/a&gt; business unit at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ceva-ip.com&#34;&gt;Ceva&lt;/a&gt;. Over the years, I went from writing (primarily) Python, to Java, and now back to Python. I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/davidkun/clojure-exercises&#34;&gt;dabbling with Clojure&lt;/a&gt; outside of work and would love to one day get paid to write Clojure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
