<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>david.kun</title>
    <link>https://davidkun.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on david.kun</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://davidkun.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate</title>
      <link>https://davidkun.github.io/posts/2024-11-24-accelerate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidkun.github.io/posts/2024-11-24-accelerate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;_accelerate-building-and-scaling-high-performing-technology-organizations_&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Accelerate: Building and Scaling High Performing Technology Organizations&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Organizations need to accelerate delivery, engagement, and responses to remain competitive. Software is at the heart of the acceleration. To improve software delivery, companies need to focus on capabilities, not maturity models. Capability models focus on key outcomes, not vanity metrics, unrelated to business outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;measuring-performance&#34;&gt;Measuring Performance&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Traditional attempts to measure the performance of software teams, usually focus on productivity and in general suffer from two mistakes: focusing on outputs (instead of outcomes) and measuring individual performance (instead of team performance). The following measures focus on global outcomes:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effective Interviewing</title>
      <link>https://davidkun.github.io/posts/2024-10-27-interviewing-kahneman/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidkun.github.io/posts/2024-10-27-interviewing-kahneman/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;effective-interviewing&#34;&gt;Effective Interviewing&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Thinking-Fast-Slow-Daniel-Kahneman/dp/0374533555&#34;&gt;Thinking, Fast and Slow&lt;/a&gt;, Daniel Kahneman gives us a detailed overview of our mind, how we think, our biases, and clever experiments for figuring this stuff out.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;bluf&#34;&gt;BLUF&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Overview of Kahneman’s advice for hiring effectively:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;First, select a few traits that are prerequisites for success in the position (technical proficiency, engaging personality, reliability, etc.). Six (6) dimensions is a good upper limit.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The traits should be as independent from each other as possible.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You should be able to assess the traits reliably by asking a few factual questions.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;List the questions for each trait and think about how you’ll score it, e.g. on a 1-5 scale a. have an idea of what you’d call “very weak” or “very strong”.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Score each trait before going to the next, and don’t skip around.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To evaluate the candidate, add up the 6 scores and firmly resolve to hire the candidate who scored highest, even if there’s another one whom you like better.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;Context&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thinking, Fast and Slow&lt;/em&gt;, by Daniel Kahneman, explains the way we think:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extreme Ownership (book notes)</title>
      <link>https://davidkun.github.io/posts/2023-03-11-extreme-ownership-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidkun.github.io/posts/2023-03-11-extreme-ownership-notes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;willink-jocko-and-leif-babin-_extreme-ownership-how-us-navy-seals-lead-and-win_-st-martins-press-2017&#34;&gt;Willink, Jocko, and Leif Babin. &lt;em&gt;Extreme ownership: How US Navy SEALs lead and win&lt;/em&gt;. St. Martin&amp;rsquo;s Press, 2017.&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;leadership-the-single-most-important-factor&#34;&gt;Leadership: The Single Most Important Factor&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most leadership books focus on individual practices / personal character traits. But &lt;em&gt;without a team there can be no leadership&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;a group of individuals working to accomplish a mission&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Leadership requires a diverse team of people in various groups to execute highly complex missions in order to achieve strategic goals&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep Work (book notes)</title>
      <link>https://davidkun.github.io/posts/2023-03-04-deep-work-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidkun.github.io/posts/2023-03-04-deep-work-notes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;newport-cal-_deep-work-rules-for-focused-success-in-a-distracted-world_-hachette-uk-2016&#34;&gt;Newport, Cal. &lt;em&gt;Deep work: Rules for focused success in a distracted world&lt;/em&gt;. Hachette UK, 2016.&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The notes in &lt;a href=&#34;#part-i&#34;&gt;Part I&lt;/a&gt; focus largely on context and provide definitions (what is Deep Work and why is it meaningful). &lt;a href=&#34;#part-ii&#34;&gt;Part II&lt;/a&gt; describes the four rules of Deep Work. If you&amp;rsquo;re in a rush to start working Deeply, jump straight to &lt;a href=&#34;#work-deeply&#34;&gt;Rule 1: Work Deeply&lt;/a&gt; for guidance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-i&#34;&gt;Part I&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deep Work&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Professional activities performed in a state of distraction-free concentration that push your cognitive capabilities to their limits. These efforts create new value, improve your skills, and are hard to replicate.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>thoughts on OOP design principles</title>
      <link>https://davidkun.github.io/posts/2022-03-18-solid-design-principles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidkun.github.io/posts/2022-03-18-solid-design-principles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I got a LinkedIn marketing email that actually caught my eye: &amp;ldquo;take a LinkedIn &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/a507663/linkedin-skill-assessments?lang=en&#34;&gt;skills assessment&lt;/a&gt; to show recruiters you are in the top 30% for that skill set.&amp;rdquo; I honestly didn&amp;rsquo;t care about getting a &amp;ldquo;badge&amp;rdquo;, but I was genuinely curious to see what kind of questions would be asked.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On their help page, they explain that assessments are created by &amp;ldquo;subject matter experts&amp;rdquo; and questions are peer-reviewed. I was hoping that I could find interesting material to incorporate into our evolving technical interview process. Instead, it got me thinking (and writing) about OOP design principles&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>influences</title>
      <link>https://davidkun.github.io/posts/influences/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidkun.github.io/posts/influences/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We all stand on the shoulders of others. Our ability to communicate and persist our ideas and discoveries has undoubtedly had a substantial impact on our technological and social evolution.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I keep track of the books, blogs, and videos that left a mark on me and impacted my growth and development.&#xA;I do this partly to keep records (e.g., so I can go back and refresh my memory), partly to have a curated list for new developers who are interested in career growth, and partly for the potential of identifying patterns (meta-learning).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Math Braintrainer</title>
      <link>https://davidkun.github.io/projects/math-brain-trainer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidkun.github.io/projects/math-brain-trainer/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surprise Surprise</title>
      <link>https://davidkun.github.io/articles/article/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidkun.github.io/articles/article/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;thank-you-for-your-support&#34;&gt;Thank you for your support!&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hello. If you like this template, I&amp;rsquo;d be happy to get a &lt;a href=&#34;https://ko-fi.com/heycharlola&#34;&gt;coffee donation&lt;/a&gt; :)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://davidkun.github.io/images/thankyou.png&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
