<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Books on david.kun</title>
    <link>https://davidkun.github.io/tags/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Books on david.kun</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://davidkun.github.io/tags/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Extreme Ownership (book notes)</title>
      <link>https://davidkun.github.io/posts/2023-03-11-extreme-ownership-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidkun.github.io/posts/2023-03-11-extreme-ownership-notes/</guid>
      <description>Willink, Jocko, and Leif Babin. Extreme ownership: How US Navy SEALs lead and win. St. Martin&amp;rsquo;s Press, 2017. Leadership: The Single Most Important Factor Most leadership books focus on individual practices / personal character traits. But without a team there can be no leadership.&#xA;Team: a group of individuals working to accomplish a mission.&#xA;Leadership requires a diverse team of people in various groups to execute highly complex missions in order to achieve strategic goals</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep Work (book notes)</title>
      <link>https://davidkun.github.io/posts/2023-03-04-deep-work-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidkun.github.io/posts/2023-03-04-deep-work-notes/</guid>
      <description>Newport, Cal. Deep work: Rules for focused success in a distracted world. Hachette UK, 2016. The notes in Part I focus largely on context and provide definitions (what is Deep Work and why is it meaningful). Part II describes the four rules of Deep Work. If you&amp;rsquo;re in a rush to start working Deeply, jump straight to Rule 1: Work Deeply for guidance.&#xA;Part I Deep Work: Professional activities performed in a state of distraction-free concentration that push your cognitive capabilities to their limits.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>influences</title>
      <link>https://davidkun.github.io/posts/influences/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidkun.github.io/posts/influences/</guid>
      <description>We all stand on the shoulders of others. Our ability to communicate and persist our ideas and discoveries has undoubtedly had a substantial impact on our technological and social evolution.&#xA;I keep track of the books, blogs, and videos that left a mark on me and impacted my growth and development. I do this partly to keep records (e.g., so I can go back and refresh my memory), partly to have a curated list for new developers who are interested in career growth, and partly for the potential of identifying patterns (meta-learning).</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
