<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Productivity on david.kun</title>
    <link>https://davidkun.github.io/tags/productivity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Productivity on david.kun</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://davidkun.github.io/tags/productivity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate</title>
      <link>https://davidkun.github.io/posts/2024-11-24-accelerate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidkun.github.io/posts/2024-11-24-accelerate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;_accelerate-building-and-scaling-high-performing-technology-organizations_&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Accelerate: Building and Scaling High Performing Technology Organizations&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Organizations need to accelerate delivery, engagement, and responses to remain competitive. Software is at the heart of the acceleration. To improve software delivery, companies need to focus on capabilities, not maturity models. Capability models focus on key outcomes, not vanity metrics, unrelated to business outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;measuring-performance&#34;&gt;Measuring Performance&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Traditional attempts to measure the performance of software teams, usually focus on productivity and in general suffer from two mistakes: focusing on outputs (instead of outcomes) and measuring individual performance (instead of team performance). The following measures focus on global outcomes:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep Work (book notes)</title>
      <link>https://davidkun.github.io/posts/2023-03-04-deep-work-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidkun.github.io/posts/2023-03-04-deep-work-notes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;newport-cal-_deep-work-rules-for-focused-success-in-a-distracted-world_-hachette-uk-2016&#34;&gt;Newport, Cal. &lt;em&gt;Deep work: Rules for focused success in a distracted world&lt;/em&gt;. Hachette UK, 2016.&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The notes in &lt;a href=&#34;#part-i&#34;&gt;Part I&lt;/a&gt; focus largely on context and provide definitions (what is Deep Work and why is it meaningful). &lt;a href=&#34;#part-ii&#34;&gt;Part II&lt;/a&gt; describes the four rules of Deep Work. If you&amp;rsquo;re in a rush to start working Deeply, jump straight to &lt;a href=&#34;#work-deeply&#34;&gt;Rule 1: Work Deeply&lt;/a&gt; for guidance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-i&#34;&gt;Part I&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deep Work&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Professional activities performed in a state of distraction-free concentration that push your cognitive capabilities to their limits. These efforts create new value, improve your skills, and are hard to replicate.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
